<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Burge | Software Engineeer</title>
    <description>The personal website and blog of John Burge, Software Engineer in Austin, Texas.
</description>
    <link>http://burge.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://burge.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 22:50:42 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 22:50:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three Ways I'd Give Feedback on Creative Projects (Without Any Experience)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A little while back I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://webflow.com/blog/how-to-ask-for-design-feedback&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; excellent article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://webflow.com/blog&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;webflow.com&lt;/a&gt;. It’s got some great advice for how designers and other creatives should ask for feedback when, too often, the people in charge of their project just don’t feel comfortable giving their honest opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;../images/20160912/squidward.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Squidward&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;This type of feedback may be a little too blunt.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I’ve been very reserved with my feedback. I’m even reserved when my wife asks me what I want for dinner. “Oh, whatever is easy for you to make.” That answer is usually more headache than help. The point of the question is to gain usable information she can take action with, not ambiguous statements of approval that are useless in decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve often found the reason for my hesitancy in offering feedback when I’m asked is due to my lack of knowledge in that creative field. This leads to three reasons I don’t give any input at all:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s easier to defer to someone else’s judgement.&lt;/strong&gt; Especially when that other person is an expert, like the person asking for input. But sometimes expertise is a liability. Their precision and care causes them to be too emotionally attached to the work, which is why they need the input of others who are much less attached.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s hard to know how to judge work outside of my expertise.&lt;/strong&gt; I couldn’t tell you what makes one font pairing “better” than another. All I can say is what looks good to me, and I hesitate to give input to an expert on the sole basis of my feelings. I mean, they’re the expert; what can I say that makes them better at their craft?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My response to a work may be very different than someone else’s.&lt;/strong&gt; At a company I was working for, our designers built a minimalistic interface where the input buttons only appeared when you hovered over icons. A lot of people found it to be user-friendly. I didn’t. None of the inputs were where I expected them to be. That doesn’t necessarily make the design bad; that just makes me weird, and demonstrates the different ways people respond to the same work. (Now if &lt;em&gt;nobody&lt;/em&gt; could find the inputs, I think &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; would make the design genuinely bad.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, I have three responses I’ve learned to use if I’m asked to give feedback on a creative project, regardless of my familiarity with the field I’ve been asked to evaluate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-like-this-design-but-not-that-one&quot;&gt;1. “I like this design, but not that one.”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feedback is simply a gut reaction. I give input based on what appeals to my aesthetic sense. The purpose of this form of feedback is to give the person creating the work a glimpse inside my mind, describing to them what intuitively and immediately appeals to me. Even if they don’t like &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I think, it gives them valuable insight into how people similar to myself will react to their work. If I’m part of their target demographic, that makes my input all the more valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, I try to say &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; I like one design and not another, giving them something specific to work with: I don’t like the color, or the line style, or the font, or the layout. I try and give careful consideration to my intuitive reaction, offering a little more detail on why I like or dislike some part of the work. I don’t know any creative that doesn’t want to understand the psychological effects their work might have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-you-choose-to-design-this-thing-this-way&quot;&gt;2. “Why did you choose to design this thing this way?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe every design choice should have a reason. It doesn’t have to be &lt;em&gt;functional&lt;/em&gt;, but it needs to be &lt;em&gt;intentional&lt;/em&gt;. So if something looks arbitrary to me, or I don’t know why it’s there, I’ll ask. For example, if I’m editing a chapter or essay, I’d ask the writer if some sentence &lt;em&gt;needs&lt;/em&gt; to be there, or if it’s simply a restatement of a previous point. Or, if the writer makes an unclear statement, I try to let them know that I need more information and that it would help to turn their two sentences on the topic into a full paragraph. I could apply the same thought to visual works as well — for example, does this box &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a drop shadow? Is it necessary to use two colors this close in range? Picking out something to ask about doesn’t require skill in a field, just critical thought about how the thing fits in the larger context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also work to understand and accept the creator’s explanation. Even if they don’t make changes, they do need to defend their choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-reaction-to-this-is&quot;&gt;3. “My reaction to this is…”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike #1 above, this feedback is intended to highlight the way a work makes me &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; — it’s my emotional response to a piece. Granted, not everything is &lt;em&gt;intended&lt;/em&gt; to elicit an emotional reaction, but everyone has some degree of emotional response to some feature of a created work. If a poorly designed interface is frustrating, I’d share that with the UI designer. A smooth-moving, highly intuitive website that leaves me impressed with its speed and efficiency will be sure to get me talking to the JavaScript developer. I try to help people hear how their work makes me feel, so they can know if they are on the right track — or if a course correction is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creative-work-and-valuable-feedback-both-affect-the-bottom-line&quot;&gt;Creative work and valuable feedback both affect the bottom line.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creative work is difficult. But it’s important. A well-designed interface, a proper font choice, well-worded copy — all of these things contribute to the ultimate profitability of the organization the creators are working for. Which is why giving feedback (when asked, of course) is necessary, and why I try to take it very seriously, even in fields I’m not familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that in all three of these suggestions, there is no impetus on the creator to make changes to their work. The point of these suggestions is to force creatives to think about their work from an outside perspective, making sure that their work is accomplishing the intended goal of &lt;em&gt;building the thing better&lt;/em&gt;, and implementing the necessary changes whenever it’s not achieving that end.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 22:14:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://burge.io/three-ways-id-give-feedback-on-creative-projects-without-any-experience</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://burge.io/three-ways-id-give-feedback-on-creative-projects-without-any-experience</guid>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>user experience</category>
        
        
        <category>Creativity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three Reasons Apple Is Done Making Displays</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a fan of Apple’s displays since ancient times, when you needed to buy a special graphics card that connected to your motherboard via an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accelerated_Graphics_Port&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AGP slot&lt;/a&gt;. Back in those days, your Apple display connected via the proprietary &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Display_Connector&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ADC port&lt;/a&gt;, which I remember well because I had to scour the internet — and Fry’s — to find one that would work with my PowerMac G4. So I was a little sad that Apple pulled the Thunderbolt Display &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/6/23/12020510/apple-thunderbolt-display-discontinued&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;off the shelf&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year. I had hopes that last week’s event would come with the revelation of an external Retina Display; good thing those hopes weren’t strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of speculation around whether Apple might release another display, but I think there are three reasons why those of us who were wishing for one need to come to terms with the fact that Apple has moved on to greener pastures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-makes-a-conscious-effort-to-find-their-focus&quot;&gt;Apple Makes a Conscious Effort to Find their Focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most famous moves Steve Jobs made after coming back to a struggling Apple was the creation of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.casestudyinc.com/apples-four-quadrant-product-grid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;four-quadrant product grid&lt;/a&gt;. He drew four squares, and wrote “consumer” and “professional” across the top, while writing “desktop” and “portable” down the side. Those four products became Apple’s focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything else — printers, clones, licensing, and even PDAs (which, somewhat ironically, were the ancestor of Apple’s most popular product) — was cut from production. 3000 people &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macworld.com/article/2009941/steve-jobss-seven-key-decisions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lost their jobs&lt;/a&gt; as a result of Jobs’ resolve to focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to argue with the results. Nearly 20 years since those initial decisions, nobody cares that Apple no longer makes printers or allows third party manufacturers to sell cheaper versions of their hardware. They care that Apple continues innovating in the mobile, tablet, and laptop space. And while some might argue that Apple is struggling to regain their focus in recent years, “regaining” their focus is a problem that can only come from having found it to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that Apple’s focus has not included displays since 2011. It may even be the case — and this is purely speculation — that Steve Jobs was the only person on Apple’s executive team who cared about including displays in the product line. It seems more than coincidental that the year of Mr. Jobs’ passing was also the last year Apple released a display. Keeping that last display in the product lineup for as long as Apple did may have been out of respect for the late founder, but it also illustrated a second reason we’ll likely never see another Apple display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-thunderbolt-display-was-abandonware&quot;&gt;The Thunderbolt Display was Abandonware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth of the matter is that when Apple nixed the Thunderbolt Display from retailers earlier this year, it was already five years old. In tech terms, that’s a lifetime; in Apple’s terms, that’s an eon. The only proposition to be inferred from such a long time without improvement or iteration is that Apple just didn’t care about it. I suspect they didn’t really want to do away with it completely (again, possibly out of respect for Mr. Jobs), but neither did they have any interest in making it any better. So it stagnated for half a decade until Apple finally ended its run, a decision born out of Apple’s commitment to reason number three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-ditches-tech-that-isnt-useful-enough&quot;&gt;Apple Ditches Tech that Isn’t Useful Enough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a (very roughly-hewn) theory that Apple has some form of internal rubric for determining how useful a given technology is. This rubric may not even be explicitly stated, but it’s understood clearly enough by Apple’s leadership to help them determine whether a certain bit of technology meets a certain standard. If it doesn’t, Apple deems it &lt;em&gt;not useful enough&lt;/em&gt; and scraps it from their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember my junior high receiving some iMacs soon after they came out in 1998. I was surprised to discover that none of them had a floppy disk drive, which I thought was a strange choice. How in the world was I going to use my Mac-formatted floppy disks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing I didn’t realize then was that my floppy disk use was already on the decline. Apple simply accepted this trend and put the tech out of its misery on their product line. Floppy disks still had their uses at the time, but they just weren’t useful &lt;em&gt;enough&lt;/em&gt;. When the iMac came out, floppies were quickly being replaced by ZIP drives and CDs, made possible by ever-increasingly-popular CD burners. Then when 2012 rolled around and Apple released the new Macbook Pro, CDs and DVDs had become like the floppy in 1998: useful, but &lt;em&gt;not useful enough&lt;/em&gt;. At that point I had relegated the primary function of burnable DVDs — computer backups — to the Time Machine share on my home NAS. As in 1998, I still found the technology useful in some cases — but not most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s decision to ditch the headphone jack on the iPhone 7 may be a bit aggravating and somewhat inconvenient, but it’s fully within character. (The narrative Apple tried to spin around this decision was ludicrous. It doesn’t take “courage” to do the thing you usually do.) It’s useful tech, but for Apple, it’s &lt;em&gt;not useful enough&lt;/em&gt;. It takes up space in the iPhone that could be used for something newer and better. And my guess is that the Thunderbolt Display was in the same boat as the headphone jack. It’s useful, but &lt;em&gt;not useful enough&lt;/em&gt;. The resources necessary to keep it in the product line, compared with the usefulness of the technology, don’t meet the minimum requirements of Apple’s internal rubric. So Apple ditched it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-are-looking-up&quot;&gt;Things are Looking Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thunderbolt Display wasn’t perfect, but there was one thing I liked about it that nobody else could quite get right: its &lt;em&gt;unity&lt;/em&gt;. Plug in one port and a power cable, and the display became the hub of everything else. Nothing else needed plugging in to the computer. It matched Apple’s aesthetic. It streamlined the peripheral connection process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody has gotten that part of it quite right, but some are getting better. Dell is one of these. Currently I use their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dell-UltraSharp-34-Inch-LED-Lit-Monitor/dp/B00PXYRMPE/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UltraSharp U3415W&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn’t sure I was going to like it; in particular, I thought it was comically wide. But now I can’t live without it. Its color, quality, and picture are all glorious, and more than once I’ve found myself wishing my PC were powerful enough to render games on a screen that wide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dell also succeeds in fulfilling my need for unity, albeit not quite as well as the Thunderbolt Display did. All I need to do is plug in the Mini DisplayPort and one USB connector and the display becomes the hub of the computer. My USB &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Das-Keyboard-Professional-Mechanical-DASK3MKPROCLI/dp/B003ZG9T62/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Das Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; and wireless &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Master-Wireless-Mouse-Computer/dp/B00TZR3WRM/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Logitech mouse&lt;/a&gt; both run seamlessly through the Dell without a hint of latency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add up the variety of displays available on the market, from 144hz to 4K to 1440p, and it becomes clear that we need not lament the loss of the Thunderbolt Display for too long. Maybe ditching the old tech will finally help Apple regain some of their focus — like how to make Apple Music better, or somehow &lt;a href=&quot;/17-things-you-can-buy-instead-of-apples-17-000watch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;making the Apple Watch a palatable purchase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 21:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://burge.io/three-reasons-apple-is-done-making-displays</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://burge.io/three-reasons-apple-is-done-making-displays</guid>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
        <category>hardware</category>
        
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Change Your MySQL Password on Bluehost</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-change-your-mysql-password-for-wordpress&quot;&gt;How to Change Your MySQL Password for WordPress&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had a client whose WordPress site got hacked. It was a weird sort of hack, where only a small percentage of the site visitors reported suspicious activity. It was tough to reproduce, but after some digging I found more than 40 files with suspicious names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommended &lt;a href=&quot;https://sucuri.net/website-security/malware-removal&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sucuri&lt;/a&gt; site cleanup services to my client, and they were able to get his site cleaned and running smoothly again. However, they didn’t take care of the necessary business of changing login and password information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My client was able to do everything himself, but the DB password changes were beyond his knowledge. He asked me to change the passwords, which is something I’d never done with WordPress before. So I I looked into it, and figured out what I needed to do. I’ve reproduced my steps here for anyone facing the same issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wordpress-environment&quot;&gt;WordPress Environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, I will be focusing specifically on the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shared hosting with Bluehost&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple domains on one account&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have cPanel access to your Bluehost account&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have FTP access to your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;public_html&lt;/code&gt; folder on Bluehost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-your-database-username-and-password&quot;&gt;Finding Your Database Username and Password&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I set up my account at Bluehost, I went ahead with their “one-click” WordPress installation. While convenient, it didn’t actually give me all the information I needed to do the proper database administration. If you’re in the same boat, here’s a simple (though slightly convoluted) way of getting your database information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Log in to your Bluehost FTP account. If you aren’t sure how to do this, you’ll need to get your username from your account. The FTP password should be the same as your cPanel password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After logging in via FTP, navigate to the folder containing the website you want to get the database password for. If you’re on a shared hosting plan, the site in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;public_html&lt;/code&gt; folder will be the same as the main domain name on your account. Otherwise, your add-on domains will be in subfolders in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;public_html&lt;/code&gt; folder, following the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;public_html/add_on_domain_name&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once in the directory containing the WordPress install you want the DB information for, download the file named &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This file will contain the current DB name and password, and it will look something like this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot; data-lang=&quot;php&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;...
/** The name of the database for WordPress */
define('DB_NAME', 'database_name');

/** MySQL database username */
define('DB_USER', 'database_username');

/** MySQL database password */
define('DB_PASSWORD', 'database_password');

/** MySQL hostname */
define('DB_HOST', 'localhost');
...&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can probably imagine, the value following &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DB_USER&lt;/code&gt; is the database username and the value following &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DB_PASSWORD&lt;/code&gt; is the database password. Youll need these two values to change the database information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;changing-the-database-username-and-password&quot;&gt;Changing the Database Username and Password&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;backup-your-database&quot;&gt;1. Backup your database.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bluehost gives you a few choices on how to do this; my recommendation is to just download the .sql database by using phpMyAdmin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://my.bluehost.com/cgi/help/4&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Here are Bluehost’s directions&lt;/a&gt;, which give you multiple options. Here’s what I did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Log into your Bluehost cPanel account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on the sub-menu &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;home&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Underneath the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Helpful Resources&lt;/code&gt; box, make sure the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;database&lt;/code&gt; button is turned on (it should have a white background and blue text, rather than blue background and white text).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll down to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;database&lt;/code&gt; section and click on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;phpMyAdmin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This will redirect you to all of the databases Bluehost is hosting for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; sign next to your username on the left.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on the name of the database you want to back up (recall that you got the name from your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt; file).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Export&lt;/code&gt; tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Go&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will download an unencrypted .sql file, which is a SQL dump of all of your database information. You can restore to your database just in case anything screws up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;change-your-password&quot;&gt;2. Change your password.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Navigate to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://my.bluehost.com/cgi/home&lt;/code&gt; and log in if you aren’t already.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click on the sub-menu &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;databases&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/20160615/Screen Shot 2016-06-15 at 4.58.07 PM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll down and you will see a list of “Current Databases.” These are all the databases under your account. One of these should match the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DB_NAME&lt;/code&gt; value that you pulled from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the “Privileged Users” column, find the name associated with the Database that you want to change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue scrolling and you’ll see a list of “Current Users.” Find the name of the “Privileged User” for your database (this is the user from step 4; this should match the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DB_USER&lt;/code&gt; name from your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt; file).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click “Set Password” for your database user.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bluehost will direct you to a page where you rename the password for that user. They will also give you a password generator, which I suggest you use:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/20160615/Screen Shot 2016-12-10 at 2.47.50 PM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After generating a new password, make sure to &lt;strong&gt;copy and paste it to a safe, secure place&lt;/strong&gt; so that you can refer to it whenever you need it again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paste your newly-generated password in the “Password” and “Password (Again)” fields. The “Strength” indicator should be green and say “Very Strong.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click “Change Password.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;optional-step-reload-your-site&quot;&gt;3. Optional Step: Reload your site.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, you could check your progress by attempting to reload your WordPress website. You don’t really need to, so if you just want to finish the process, jump ahead to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you decide to reload your site, you should only see one message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Error connecting to database”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is actually good! (At least, at this point in time.) This means that your WordPress site – the database “user” – is trying to connect to your MySQL database with the &lt;em&gt;old&lt;/em&gt; password. But the database is refusing the connection because it expects the “user” to be submitting the &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s make sure the user is submitting the new password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-your-wp-config-file&quot;&gt;4. Update your wp-config file.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, &lt;strong&gt;make a copy&lt;/strong&gt; of your original &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt; file. You will need to reference the original just in case something goes wrong!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the line that says &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;define('DB_PASSWORD', 'database_password');&lt;/code&gt; (line 9 in the example below):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot; data-lang=&quot;php&quot;&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border-spacing: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot; style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;...
/** The name of the database for WordPress */
define('DB_NAME', 'database_name');

/** MySQL database username */
define('DB_USER', 'database_username');

/** MySQL database password */
define('DB_PASSWORD', 'database_password');

/** MySQL hostname */
define('DB_HOST', 'localhost');
...&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;database_password&lt;/code&gt; value to the new password that you created in step 7 above. Re-upload the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt; file and overwrite the existing one. &lt;strong&gt;Remember to upload it to the correct directory if you have multiple Bluehost users!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;confirming-its-all-good&quot;&gt;Confirming It’s All Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go to the homepage of your Bluehost-hosted website. Do a hard refresh of your site (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ctrl + F5&lt;/code&gt; on Windows and Linux, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cmd + shift + R&lt;/code&gt; on Mac) to clear the site cache. This ensures that the server re-processes and re-serves all of that page’s content. If you followed all the steps above, it should load exactly like it did before – except now, your site is using the new password to access your MySQL database! Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major frustrations about this process is when you change the password of your database user in Bluehost’s control panel, it doesn’t automatically update your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt; file with the changes. There is probably a good reason for this (after all, you don’t want your Bluehost control panel taking over your WordPress back-end), but its a good example of one of the many nuances of managing a WordPress site. Every time you update something that your site depends on, but is actually independent of your site (such as the MySQL database), you need to make sure you don’t forget to update the associated setting in your site config.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it! I’d love to hear from you if you found this guide helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 18:55:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://burge.io/how-to-change-your-mysql-password-on-bluehost</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://burge.io/how-to-change-your-mysql-password-on-bluehost</guid>
        
        <category>bluehost</category>
        
        <category>mysql</category>
        
        
        <category>Databases</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Layoffs Sold &quot;Me&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently my organization went through layoffs, which were about as fun as receiving a root canal from teenager with a bad case of ADD hopped up on six cups of coffee using a rusty ice pick while sitting on a hive of fire ants for cushioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I didn’t even lose my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This marks the second time in my career that layoffs have come at an organization I was a part of, and the second time that I avoided the chopping block. But surviving a corporate cull like that rarely diffuses the tension. In my experience, it has the opposite effect: it introduces a sense of dread (paranoia?) that never goes away, and is often reinforced by the sickly green florescent lighting that you never noticed before, but now seems absolutely everywhere. It makes you wonder if someone was actually paid to put that lighting in, and if so, you know you could do a better job of it. Which makes you depressed, because then you start to wonder why you’re even with your company if you could be putting in nice lighting. Which then makes you wish you actually had been one of the ones who &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; get laid off, because at least then you could bring in a paycheck at your fallback job in interior lighting while working on your dream job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, at least, that’s how most people think about layoffs. That’s how I used to, anyway. This time, however, I accepted that the layoffs my organization went through are not some dark monster hiding in the shadows like a boogeyman; rather, they forced me to realize what I had tried hard to deny, and they reminded me of a hard truth I knew but found convenient and comfortable to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-realization&quot;&gt;The Realization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These layoffs forced me to realize that everyone is their own business, and everyone is their own brand. Which means that everyone is in both product development — the product of “you” — and sales of that product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing I never have been, and never aspire to be, it’s a salesman. So the first time I heard that everyone is in sales (I think it was from Dave Ramsey), I didn’t want to accept it. It’s hard to describe how much I hate selling. I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; it. I could be the world’s leading expert on goldfish, but if I had to sell to someone who &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; a goldfish, I would spend a long part of that very rough conversation just trying to remember exactly what sort of fish I’m selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the fact of the matter is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.garyvaynerchuk.com/three-huge-business-mistakes-you-might-make-1167763013.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;if you can’t sell, you’re out of business&lt;/a&gt;. Layoffs are a reminder that you just went out of the “you” business, and you won’t be back in the “you” business until you can sell yourself. Which, of course, means that the “you” that you are selling needs to be better than all of the other “thems” that are competing with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-reminder&quot;&gt;The Reminder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These layoffs reminded me that change is inevitable, that it comes on us when we least expect it, and that it happens when it’s the most inconvenient. My coworkers and I thought that our future at the company was going to last long enough to collectively build new value; unfortunately, we all discovered that we’re actually expendable. The only thing that differentiated me from my fellows that received their severances was that, for some reason, the “me” I was offering to my company was more appealing than the “thems” that my coworkers were selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sounds depressing, but I don’t see it that way. I take it as an indicator that someone in the company’s leadership is finally recognizing that resources are finite and tradeoffs are inevitable. I like to remain hopeful that the leadership will maintain consistent awareness of their new-found realization and do what they can to sell more, since, if they can’t sell, they’re out of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-reaction&quot;&gt;The Reaction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial reaction to our layoffs was visceral: they suck. It sucks when people lose their jobs. It sucks even more when the people who lose their jobs are people you’ve worked alongside for several years. In my situation, the sting was driven home by the fact that this team I’d worked with was successful. We had helped an enormous company build a product that not only competes in a space with the likes of Apple and Microsoft, but it was one of the rare parts of our parent company that, unlike the company as a whole, was in the black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But eventually I got over that reaction, and decided to accept that the only sure thing is what is in my control — which, at the end of the day, is only me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the kicker: I &lt;em&gt;decided to accept&lt;/em&gt; the truths that our layoffs made ever-present: we are all in the business of ourselves, and change comes upon us when we least expect it and when we don’t want it. I can’t control change, but I can control me. I can continue to develop a better “me” and continue getting better at selling “me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I made some calls, sent some emails, and sold “me” to a different company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t begrudge layoffs, and I don’t fault executives for making them happen. Nevertheless, layoffs are insidious, because they plant seeds of distrust about the future of an organization. Even if layoffs allow the company to continue functioning, without a &lt;em&gt;visible&lt;/em&gt; fundamental change in the company’s culture and practices, you will never regain the trust of the survivors. They will believe that, come the same time next year, their jobs will be the next to disappear. And the layoffs they just witnessed provide all the evidence they need to back up those beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than wait for the change to come, people who know it’s inevitable — people like me — will leverage the things they can control, make choices to build the product of “them,” sell it to another company, and be more than happy to accept payment for services rendered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, if a company can’t sell themselves to “me,” I certainly won’t hire them for 40 hours of my time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 22:35:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://burge.io/how-layoffs-sold-me</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://burge.io/how-layoffs-sold-me</guid>
        
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading Code Made Me a Better Person</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve known a handful of people in my life who aren’t very good readers. They stumbled through words, and seemed to need more than a second’s pause between each one (which is very long when someone is reading out loud). Listening to them read was a torturous experience for me, and I’m sure it was even worse for them. The really bad part of it was that there was always some part of me that was happy I wasn’t like that. I’ve always been a strong reader, able to go at any speed I need to. When I read out loud, I have an intuitive sense of where to place the proper emphasis and flourish. It’s rare for me to have the need to read a line twice. I know that there are a lot of people who can’t read as well as I do, and who don’t enjoy it as much as I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an ability I’d come to take for granted. And while my immature self would never admit it (and my more mature self still has a hard time admitting it), I’m certain that there were times I questioned people’s intelligence who didn’t have my ability to read. I dared to presume that I knew what a person could be and do simply because they did not have this one specific, local ability that I have; an ability that, while better than average, is so far from exceptional that it will never be recognized in any record books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, refreshingly, code unseated me from this grand high horse I’d come to assume was mine by right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning to read code knocked me down, planted me on my back with my feet in the air, and put me squarely in the seat of those readers who stumble through each word, frustrated with themselves, who feel that overwhelming sense of “I’ll never get this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning to read code did this to me because there is only one way to read code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;hate&lt;/em&gt; reading slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading slowly takes time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the years I’ve had to get better at reading print and prose, I’ve become quite good at reading. This has made it easy for me to fly my eyes over a paragraph and easily get the gist of it. It’s also made me more impatient, a character flaw with which the amount of content we’re thrown every day has not helped. For most content, especially content on the web, I skim. Like everyone else with a computer and Internet connection, I’m inundated with so much content on a multiplicity of feeds that I simply don’t read everything. I judge articles by their titles, and from that determine whether I’m going to give the article the dignity of a gloss-over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually this goes one of two ways. The first is that I start “reading” (skimming) the article, then get bored by the end of the second paragraph. I move on to the next thing. The second is that I actually manage to skim to the end of the article, think to myself, “That was pretty good,” and then move on to the next anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is lazy. It’s downright arrogant. It’s an abuse of a gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code stubbornly refuses to accept my laziness. It makes me work hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code is thorough. It is precise. It is unforgiving. If I read “wsetren” when someone actually meant “western,” I don’t miss what they meant. I subconsciously rearrange the word into the proper order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code does not give half a flying unicorn’s rainbow fart about my ability to infer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code is selfish, self-absorbed, and egotistical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code demands my undivided attention, and has not reserved forgiveness for that time I read “O” as “zero.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code has demanded that I pay careful attention to what I’m reading, and punishes me for making a mistake in the code that I’m writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code is a fascinating teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real reason I want to read code quickly is because I’m looking for a quick fix. I want to understand how a great app or website is written, right now, and I want to implement my own version — right now. But anything worth doing well takes time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creation is one of the things most worth doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creation of art, creation of story, creation of of an application — all of it is worth it in the end, but only for the people who have the patience to accept that the finished creation is worth more than the time it took to make it. It’s worth it only if you are willing to let code teach you with all of its selfishness and brutality and utter lack of forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code put me in my place. It made me remember that I am a student and that I cannot bring this skill I’ve come to take for granted with me, expecting it to serve me as well for code as it has for prose. Code slaps it out of my hand, punches me in the face, knocks me on my back, and makes me get up and take one step. And then another. And only one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code made me a better person because it reminded me that I’m at a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://burge.io/reading-code-made-me-a-better-person</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://burge.io/reading-code-made-me-a-better-person</guid>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
        <category>ruby</category>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        
        <category>Engineering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>17 Things You Can Buy Instead of Apple's $17,000 Watch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I found it hard to believe that Apple has a Watch model that will run you &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.apple.com/us/buy-watch/apple-watch-edition?product=MJ3G2LL/A&amp;amp;step=detail#&quot;&gt;$17,000&lt;/a&gt;, until I saw it for myself. I love Apple products, but not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly, that sticker price is ridiculous. On a normal day I’m somewhat conservative with my spending habits, so when I saw that price I about keeled over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should be clear that I’m not ready to discount the Apple Watch as a game-changing device. I did that with the iPod, iPhone, and iPad. I ended up owning all three. I may very well own an Apple Watch within the next year or two. It’s taken me longer than it should have, but I’ve decided I’m not that credible when it comes to giving an accurate prediction of what Apple’s devices have the capability of doing, for both individuals and popular culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do, however, have some credibility when it comes to managing money properly, and that price is &lt;em&gt;ludicrous&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead, I’ve decided to compile a list of things you could buy with that $17,000 - one item for each $1000 on the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 full years of tuition, books, and supplies at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fullerton.edu/financialaid/appinfo/cost.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;California State University Fullerton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A down payment on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trulia.com/property/3032900129-4623-Credo-Ln-Austin-TX-78725&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this 3 bed/3 bath home&lt;/a&gt; in Austin, TX.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chris Guillibeau’s book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/100-Startup-Reinvent-Living-Create/dp/0307951529/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1426092368&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=100+startup&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The $100 Startup&lt;/a&gt;, and 169 businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 12-week &lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly/education/web-development-immersive/los-angeles&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Web Development Immersive&lt;/a&gt; at General Assembly, Apple’s new top-end &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.apple.com/us/buy-mac/macbook/space-gray-512gb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Macbook&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trulia.com/rental/3191521185-1725-Ocean-Front-Walk-Santa-Monica-CA-90401&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;3 month’s rent&lt;/a&gt; in Santa Monica.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seven purebred &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suburbanbullies.com/availablepuppies.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;English Bulldog puppies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new &lt;a href=&quot;http://automobiles.honda.com/fit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Honda Fit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mortarinvestments.eu/products/armoured-vehicles-4/saurer-4k-4fa-apc-361#currency=USD&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;armored personnel carrier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A giant &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.poshtots.com/gifts/seasonal/holiday-gifts-and-toys/the-grand-crimson-dragon/16/3616/3432/28638/poshproductdetail.aspx?AID=11555276&amp;amp;PID=5314042&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;plush dragon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://aquaxflyer.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;water-powered jetpack&lt;/a&gt; and brand new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pwctrader.com/listing/2015-Bombardier-SPARK-2UP-114039168&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sea-Doo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A regulation-size &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.titleboxing.com/title-mma-competition-8-sided-cage.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UFC Octagon&lt;/a&gt; fighting cage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opulentitems.com/gifts/mensgifts/air-boards.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;personal hovercraft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two Sony &lt;a href=&quot;http://store.sony.com/78.6-diag-x900b-premium-4k-ultra-hd-tv-zid27-XBR79X900B/cat-27-catid-XBR-4K-Ultra-HD-TVs;pgid=PKZgS32BNmpSRpUu8z.NS0w10000MKsQjIrH;sid=XCsNN1Fms2oBNwRuEpxqM2NsvJ39vhenpxZpA-F6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;4K Ultra&lt;/a&gt; TVs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.poshtots.com/baby-furniture/posh/ultimate-posh/sunken-viking-ship-bed-and-deep-sea-mural/18/1376/1360/25892/poshproductdetail.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Viking Ship bed&lt;/a&gt; for your child (to go with the plush dragon).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This Zombie- and End-of-the-World-proof &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polaris.com/en-us/atv-quad/2014/sportsman-wv850-ho-avalanche-gray&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ATV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A target-tracking &lt;a href=&quot;http://tracking-point.com/precision-guided-firearms/precision-guided-bolt-action-308&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;big game rifle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hammacher.com/Product/Default.aspx?sku=12121&amp;amp;promo=Sports-Leisure-Outdoor-Fun&amp;amp;catid=231&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;inflatable military obstacle course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, Dave Ramsey’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daveramsey.com/fpu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Financial Peace University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for 15 people, and a $1000 emergency fund for each of them, because someone who spends $17,000 on an Apple Watch might not be qualified to handle money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 23:23:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://burge.io/17-things-you-can-buy-instead-of-apples-17-000watch</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://burge.io/17-things-you-can-buy-instead-of-apples-17-000watch</guid>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>apple watch</category>
        
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Don't Want Technology to Solve a Problem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought an iPhone 6 Plus. I love everything about it, including the ridiculous size. I suppose I didn’t need to spend so much money on it; I could have bought an Android, but I’ve always had an aversion to that platform for one very specific reason:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was built as an alternative to the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’m aware that that’s precisely why most people like it. They also like it because it’s cheaper and it’s on every mobile carrier. Android phones were also the first to offer larger sizes that Apple didn’t adopt until the iPhone 6. In many cases it even has more memory (although it’s not as good as iOS in using that memory).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here is what I find striking about Android: I’ve never met a die-hard Android fan. I’ve never met anyone whose fervor for Android reminds you of the Apple fanboys and fangirls who line up in front of an Apple store weeks ahead of a product release. I’ve never met a single individual who truly, honestly, certainly, unwaveringly believes that the Android platform is the best and only solution for how mobile devices should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do, however, know plenty of Android fans who dislike Apple. And that’s the perfect symptom of the problem plaguing Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Apple released the Macintosh in 1984, it was the realization of a vision: technology should not only be accessible for the masses, but it should be a work of art in itself. Steve Jobs was even concerned about the interior of the computer because he knew what was in there, and he couldn’t tolerate good design outside with poor design inside. Years later, the iPod continued this vision: it took advances in audio compression technology and coupled those with unique design to give everybody 1000 songs in your pocket. The iPhone did it again: it took the best that cellular and wireless networking technology had to offer, united it with the iPod, and what resulted was a unique, innovative piece of technology that has influenced hardware, software, and the web ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always understood Apple’s approach to be philosophical at its core. The way Apple creates technology is with a commitment to the premise that a specific category of things - computers and personal electronics - are the very best they can be only when the aesthetics, hardware and software are built in unison with one another. It’s a vision that few have attempted to duplicate and even fewer have succeeded at, because it’s a vision that requires a clear, concentrated focus. It requires a focus on what the best computer or device of a certain type should be, it requires a very specific vision of what that computer or device should do, and together those inform the vision of how that computer or device should be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the technology that is created originates with a vision of the right way this technology should be.
Naturally, the extension of this is that every part of the device is built with focused intentionality: if a battery can only be a certain size in the device, then the OS can only run so many background processes at once, or else the battery will lose charge at a rate that makes it highly inefficient for the user. Or if, as mentioned above, the iPhone has half the RAM of an Android phone, it can still be twice as efficient because the OS was built around it, tailored specifically to using that much RAM, which has only a specific amount of power draw, again influencing battery charge. Every part of the device is built with the motivation that any other way is inferior, and that any other way of building it does not reflect the nature of the device itself. Any other way is not the way this thing should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android did not exist until someone asked, “Is there anyone who makes an iPhone, but cheaper?” When contrasted with Apple’s vision of how technology should be, this question sounds crass and grating. It sounds like the focus is not on presenting an alternative vision of the way technology should be, but rather on creating something that is made for no other reason than to be sold in a niche to generate cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem I see plaguing Android is that it is an opportunistic reaction to a focused vision for how the world should be. And regardless of how well-made something might be, or how good something is at solving a problem, it seems to me that nothing can be truly exceptional if its conception is reactionary. The things we make, and the technology we create, can never be a proper reflection of our belief in the way the world should be if the only reason we make it is because we see an opportunity to sell something that is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; thing &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the iPhone was released, there was a problem: people wanted the function of the iPhone, but they did not want to pay more money for the iPhone. So, Google saw the opportunity to launch an alternative, and to pursue a model proven to keep cost down: license the technology to manufacturers who already had supply chains in place, and let them dictate its implementation. The resulting products were certainly cheaper, and more well-suited to a consumer who had the problem of not wanting to spend the money required to buy an iPhone. Android solved their problem. But that’s all it did. That’s why I’ve never met an Android user who was sold on the platform, head over heels. That’s why I’ve met a lot of Android users who dislike Apple, but none who believe that Android is a proper reflection of the way that mobile technology should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should make it clear that I don’t think there is a problem with someone owning an Android device. There are lots of very good, practical, long-term reasons to own an Android. The one that strikes closest to my own heart would be the example of the individual who is on a strict budget because she’s paying off debt and getting herself out of a hole of her own making. If that’s her focus - and living without debt &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the way that the world should be - then she can’t afford to spend top dollar when cheaper alternatives are available. To this extent, owning an Android device might actually help her achieve her vision of how her life should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even so, in my own experience I’ve never been able to justify to myself spending the money on a device I’m dispassionate about. I want my technology to be representative and reflective of the way I choose to live my life and do my work: it needs to start with a vision grounded in a clear philosophy. The philosophy needs to define some way the world should be, and the vision needs to offer a blueprint for how that philosophy is implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternative choices in products or services that are made as cheaper versions of some technology or other will always have a place in the market. Implementing a vision grounded in clear philosophy does not come cheap, and there will always be people who place higher value on the amount of money left in their wallet after the transaction than on the implementation of the vision for that technology. There’s nothing wrong with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I simply don’t think that’s the way the world should be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 21:20:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://burge.io/i-dont-want-technology-to-solve-a-problem</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://burge.io/i-dont-want-technology-to-solve-a-problem</guid>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
